A Guide to the Virginia M. Herz Currie Papers, 1934-2000
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Virginia M. Herz Currie Papers, 1934-2000
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms2001-005
3.8 cu. ft.
This collection contains watercolors executed by Virginia M. Herz Currie, as well as information pertaining to the 1995 Valiant Woman Award and a scrapbook.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
The Virginia M. Herz Currie Papers were donated to Special Collections in 2001.
Biographical Information
Virginia M. Herz was born in Minnesota in 1913. She graduated in 1936 from the University of Minnesota in Minneapolis with a degree in Interior Architecture. While in the program she met her future husband, fellow architecture student, Leonard James Currie and they married in 1937. The couple traveled over much of the world including Bogota, Columbia, Penang, Malausia, Boston, Chicago, and Blacksburg, Virginia. The American Institute of Architects elected Currie to Honorary Society Membership in recogizition of her voluntary efforts to improve the natural and built environment, and in particular for her leadership in the Blacksburg Beautification program resulting in landscaped medians throughout town. The couple had three children - Barbara, Robert, and Elizabeth. Currie died in 2006 at the age of 92.
Scope and Content
A graduate of the architectural program at the University of Minnesota, the Currie Papers contain watercolors probably done while she was a student in the 1930s. There is also a scrapbook from a neighborhood beautification project in Chicago in 1966 and the 1995 Valiant Woman Award.
Contents List
- "Stuart library" Virginia M. Herz 1-26-35 project no. 4, interior design "mention" (25" by 37"), ca.1930s. (Oversize 1)
- Unlabeled (24 .25" x 38"), ca.1930s. (Oversize 2)
- "A Moderne Hotel Suite" Virginia Herz, Interior Design, Second prob. "(short)" (25" x 38.25"), ca.1930s. (Oversize 3)
- "Louis XVI Bedroom" Virginia M. Herz, project no. 6, March 16, 1934 "mention" (25" x 38"), ca.1930s. (Oversize 4)
- Virginia M. Herz, new grade II proj. "credit +" (24" x 32"), ca.1930s. (Oversize 5)
- Virginia Herz, 1934-5 (25.25" x 38.75"), ca.1930s. (Oversize 6)
- Virginia Herz, first advanced project, April 23, 1933 "credit" (27" x 38.5"), ca.1930s. (Oversize 7)
- Unlabeled (15.5" x 24"), ca.1930s. (Oversize 8)
- Biographical Information, 2006 and undated (Folder 1)
- Valiant Woman Award Materials, 1995. (Folder 2)
- Scrapbook: "Chicago Beautiful and the Near West Side," 19 leaves; 24 photographs (most by L.J. Currie), 1966. (Folder 3-4)
- Landmarks Preservation Council of Illinois Materials, 2000, n.d. (Folder 5)